one of the most simple pieces of gym
equipment may also be one of the most
functional pieces of equipment I'm
talking about a good old-fashioned
kettlebell you can improve your cardio
full body strength mobility and even
coordination I've been getting after it
with the again faster kettlebell so
today I'm going to break down my
findings for y'all
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbin garage gym and for today's review
I've got a kettlebell from again faster
in this review I'm going to take you
through everything that these
kettlebells have to offer from the price
some features of course the pros and the
cons but what would we be doing here if
I did not include who should and who
should not purchase one of these to add
to their home gym but before I get
started we've reviewed a lot of
kettlebells on barbin.com and if you
want to browse our best list just simply
search bar Bend best kettlebells you can
find out which ones we like the best but
also which ones will suit you the best
all right let's get to it
foreign
[Music]
so let's start with what I like about
these kettlebells so nobody wants a bad
grip when it comes to throwing weight
around in the gym and that's especially
true with kettlebells because you're
quite literally throwing them around
while you're working out with them so a
bad grip really isn't something you
should be worried about here because
again faster crafted their kettlebells
with a texture powder coat finish so
it's going to give you a nice grip on
its own but if you want to utilize some
chalk you can easily do so it's going to
mix well with these kettlebells the
handle is also it's a little bit flat on
the top and the sides if you look up
close so it might feel even better in
your hands and the wide grip handle is
also going to easily accommodate not
only for single-handed grips but for
two-handed grips so you can easily do
some goblet squats with these no problem
so the cast iron used here was made with
a single pour so what that means is this
is one solid piece so you don't have to
worry about the handle and the bell ever
coming loose because they're not welded
together there's no plugs here like you
can often find with some kettlebells
made of lesser quality the handle is
also color coded it's pretty standard
with kettlebells nowadays but it's still
a nice touch because you can easily pick
and choose which kettlebell you want and
get right to working out since this is
not coated in rubber the bottom is nice
and flat and once you set it down it's
not going to move it's just going to sit
flat on whatever surface you have it on
and there's weight options ranging from
nine pounds up to 70 pounds so there's a
good chance you can find one of these
kettlebells to suit your specific needs
plus you can purchase these individually
like I have here or you can get them in
sets so you have two different sets to
work from Individual set or the set of
pairs so when I say individual visual
set you get one kettlebell for each
weight option once again that's nine to
seventy pounds and with the pairs you
get two of each
[Music]
okay so now you might ask me Jake what
about those potential Cons with these
kettlebells okay so let's start with the
weight yeah up to 70 pounds that might
be enough resistance for you but if it's
not well
tough luck because that's as high as
these go if you need something heavier
than that then you're gonna have to look
elsewhere some companies actually offer
up to 200 pounds for their kettlebells
and since these are not competition
kettlebells they're not uniform in size
so as you go up and wait the size is
going to also increase and that could be
you know some sort of an issue for
specific exercises for some of y'all if
that is the case you do want them
specifically to be the same size well
you're definitely gonna have to go find
yourself some competition kettlebells
they're also not cheap so this 53 pound
kettlebell it's right around 100 you can
find some other kettlebells that are
really similar in quality nearly
identical for a little bit cheaper but
it is worth mentioning that you do get
free shipping from again faster while
some of those other companies might not
offer that free shipping so that's
something you got to remember as well
and let's be honest available space is
always an issue when it comes to workout
equipment so if you don't have enough
space for a full set or maybe even for
one of these then I would definitely
suggest getting yourself an adjustable
kettlebell system or maybe even a
kettlebell grip attachment and that's
going to essentially transform any
existing dumbbells that you might have
at home into a kettlebell
foreign
[Music]
okay so let's talk about some money now
as I said you can purchase these
individually or you have two different
sets you can work with so with the
individual kettlebells the cheapest
option is in fact that nine pound
kettlebell it's gonna run you right
around 35 bucks
this 53 pound kettlebell like I said
it's about a hundred dollars in the 70
pound kettlebell it's gonna be right
around 130 bucks
now with those sets Okay so the set of
individual kettlebells remember you get
one of each that's going to run you just
under 500 if you were to get the set of
pairs it's going to be about 900 but
remember you do get free shipping from
again faster so that might relieve some
of the stress for you okay so I
definitely would not consider these
cheap but since you do in fact have the
luxury of purchasing them in two
different sets you know you could save
money in the long run as opposed to
being forced to purchase individual
kettlebells from some other companies
you know obviously workout equipment is
an investment so with these kettlebells
I mean they feel really durable really
sturdy and I think they could last you
potentially a lifetime you know just as
long as you're not tossing them on
concrete or doing something crazy
this could be the last set of
kettlebells You Really Ever Need so
that's something that's really nice in
my opinion but if they do fall out of
your budget
I would definitely just go and get
yourself an adjustable kettlebell system
but I have noticed that some of them
don't even go up to 70 pounds that's
something you got to think about too
because you'll eventually run into that
problem of your weight capping out
okay so let's talk about the build now
that went into these kettlebells now I
was not able to find the exact
dimensions for the handles online I had
to go to a different website it's not on
the again faster website so I was able
to find that this 53 pound kettlebell
it's 1.5 inches in diameter which feels
pretty accurate in my opinion feels
really similar to some other 53 pound
kettlebells out there it's just
something worth mentioning that I wasn't
able to get it exactly for you guys
today the handle is also pretty wide at
the base so it's going to easily
accommodate for any two-handed grips
you're not going to have any issue with
that at all and it's actually a bit flat
on the top as you go around right here
so I personally like that it feels
pretty good in my hands some of you
might not like that but just something I
had to bring up
the handles also color coded which is
just really nice it makes it super easy
to grab and go with your weights
especially once you memorize it you'll
be like oh that's green oh that's 53
pounds cool let's grab it and get right
to work
so the double cast iron here was also
made with one single pour so the handle
on the Belt are one solid piece you
don't have to worry about anything
coming loose over time there's no plugs
it's not welded together it's one solid
piece not going to break on you
this is not coated in rubber so it's
going to sit nice and flat there's no
seam down here nothing to get in the way
of making it sit nice and flat when you
go to set it down I personally love that
and the powder coat here it's got a nice
texture it's going to give you a pretty
good grip on its own but if you want to
utilize some chalk it's going to easily
mix with these kettlebells
all right so let's do a quick walk
around with this kettlebell now I really
like the textured powder coat they put
on here it's a nice matte black finish
it's going to look good in your gym but
it's also going to hold well with chalk
and give you a pretty good grip on its
own now with the handle up here I don't
know the exact diameter but it seems to
be about 1.5 inches or so compared to
some other kettlebells that I've used
nice and wide down here for your
two-handed grips no problem whatsoever
the top and the sides right here it's
pretty flat and that could fill
differently in your hands it could fill
it up a little bit more for some people
it might be nice you might not like it
but you know it is there it's something
that you need to know about you do have
a green color coating right here this is
to show this is the 53 pound kettlebell
that's going to change depending on
which option you use and something I
thought is kind of cool right here it's
a little bit different than other
kettlebells usually the Engravings on
the back will have of both pounds and
kilograms for each kettlebell well with
again faster they put theirs on the
front which I think it just looks kind
of cool you got the kilograms up top you
know again faster in the middle and then
the pounds underneath so that's pretty
nice and if you flip this over on its
side
this is a really wide obviously flat
base right here and there's no seam
there's also you know no other seam
anywhere else on this kettlebell without
without that seam underneath you know
nothing's getting in the way it's going
to sit nice and flat not wobble on you
but it's really nice knowing that
there's no welding right here so it just
shows you that this is one solid piece
of iron it's going to be really durable
and last you for a long time
foreign
faster kettlebells well if you do in
fact want yourself a nice durable
kettlebell which with why wouldn't you
this is a pretty good option for you to
choose from because they are in fact
made from a double cast iron and they're
molded from a single pour so the handle
and the bell one big solid piece you
don't have to worry about the two
becoming loose over time just of course
be smart don't throw them around and
drop them if you do get sweaty hands
while you're working out like myself my
Palms tend to sweat a little bit while
I'm lifting I think you'll have some
pretty good success with the textured
powder coat I personally did but also if
you have some chalk you like to use
it's gonna probably mix well with these
kettlebells as well and since you can in
fact purchase these in a set of pairs if
you have a workout buddy you all both
can use the same weight at the same time
or if you have a weight bench at home
you can also use these for bench press
[Music]
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase these kettlebells
well this is kind of a personal
preference but if you don't like the bit
of a flatness I guess you could say on
the top of these handles
definitely just go and find yourself
another kettlebell that's nice and round
there's plenty of options out there if
you don't like the texture powder coat
there's also kettlebells out there that
don't utilize a powder coat finish and
maybe you want your kettlebells to be
wrapped in rubber just to give you that
slight decreased chance of messing up
your hardwood floors or any floors
really you can find some for sure but
that doesn't mean you can just
carelessly drop them still got to be
careful with those as well and if you
want your kettlebells to be uniform in
size regardless of their weight like I
said you're not going to get that here
if that's the case that's what you
really want definitely go get yourself
some competition kettlebells
foreign
on today's review over the again faster
kettlebells these are super durable and
for the quality they're not going to
necessarily break the bank since they
are made from a single pour of double
cast iron you don't have to worry about
the handle and the bell coming loose
over time because they are in fact one
solid piece the handles are also color
coded that's just going to make it super
easy to grab and go and the base is in
fact seamless so I don't think you'll
have any trouble at all when you're
going to store them on any type of shelf
maybe even just the floor they're going
to sit nice and flat the weight does max
out at 70 pounds so if you need
something heavier than that you know
you're gonna have to look elsewhere but
for a lot of y'all watching there's some
pretty good weight options here for you
to choose from thanks for watching
everybody hope this video was helpful
showed you a little bit of what to
expect if you were to add these
kettlebells to your home gym as always
stay on the lookout for my next review
but for now head over to Barbara in.com
and you can read more on this product
just search barbend again faster
kettlebell review you can find all the
details we discussed here today I'll see
y'all next time
[Music]